<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<diff xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="../../xmllib/diff.xsd">
  <add sel="/language">
	<page id="19530201" title="Skull+Bones" descr="pirates" voice="yes">	
	  <t id="100">YAR HAR ME BOY'OS</t>
	  <!--TURRETS/WEAPONS-->
	  <t id="200">Incendiary Bomb Launcher</t>
	  <t id="201">\033#95e03b29#BMB\033X\ Incendiary Bomb Mortar</t>	  
	  <t id="202">Burst Ray Turret</t>
	  <t id="203">Rail Slugger Turret</t>	  	 
	 <!--TURRETS/WEAPONS DESCRIPTIONS-->
	  <t id="300">\033#95e03b29#L Turret\033X\ \nUnable to easily gain possession of high-tech capital ship weapons, pirate engineers designed the Incendiary Bomb Launcher as an easily producible alternative. With the name being in use for nearly a century, each iteration of the IBL is based on the design of a contemporary weapon and shares little in common with its predecessor, aside from the basic mode of operation and effect on target. The modern IBL is essentially just a massively scaled up and mildly deconstructed Plasma Cannon, hurling massive balls of high-energy plasma that destabilize and explode on impact. This explosion deals significant damage across a wide blast radius and momentarily leaves behind a burning reside that can damage the hulls of shielded targets, though the unstable nature of the projectile somewhat limits the IBL's effective range compared to similarly sized weapons.\n\nCuriously, neither of the IBL's secondary effects are intentional- in a bid to reduce the power demands of the weapon, a variety of features dedicated to safety and reliability were stripped from the Plasma Cannon design, though the negative effects of such a move are clearly of little interest to the pirates.</t>	
	  <t id="301">Size: SMALL\n Weapon Class: BOMBER\n\nThe Incendiary Bomb Mortar is a miniaturized version of capital-sized Incendiary Bomb Launcher. Just like the larger counterpart, the IBM throws unstable plasma projectiles that explode on impact and briefly leave a burning residue that can damage the hull of a shielded vessel. While it offers a remarkable amount of firepower for its size, the lack of a capital-grade power supply drastically limits the projectile's maximum range and velocity.</t>	  
	  <t id="302">As its name suggests, the Yaki Burst Ray turret incorporates the same phased-wavelength technology found on the standard fixed-mount Burst Ray. Much like the progenitor technology, the Burst Ray turret deals extra damage against exposed hull and surface components, and can partially bypass active shield layers, though this comes at the cost of a reduction in maximum effective range- a tradeoff deemed necessary in order to enhance their raiders' ability to swiftly overwhelm and disable targets when making forays through hostile space.</t>
	  <t id="303">The Yaki Rail Slugger turret is a straightfoward modification, mounting a Paranid-designed Rail Slugger onto a medium-class turret mount. Though it has extremely poor tracking capability, the weapon boasts a best-in-class effective range and lethally fast projectiles, giving Yaki raiders an extremely effective armament to harrass targets while on the offensive or covering rear arcs to deter pursuers.</t>		  
	  <!--STATION MODULES-->
	  <t id="400">PLACEHOLDER</t>
	  <!--SHIPS-->
	  <t id="700">Galleon</t>
	  <t id="701">Blastclaw</t>
	  <t id="702">Brigantine</t>	
	  <t id="703">Carrack</t>		
	  <t id="704">Marauder</t> 
	  <t id="705">(Osprey Raider){20101,20401} {20111,1001}</t>
	  <t id="706">(Vulture Raider){20101,20501} {20111,1001}</t> 
	  <!--SHIP DESCRIPTIONS-->
	  <t id="800">Scale Plate pirates have long been rumored offer a premium to employ Teladi builders for remote jobs, only to commandeer their vessels after the work is complete. While the majority of these captured construction ships are swiftly broken up for scrap to turn a quick credit and recoup costs, recent shifts in internal culture of the Scale Plate Pact have resulted in a different fate for some of the vessels. The growing trend of organization and cooperation among Pact pirates has led to the emergence of pirate warlords, commanding of large fleets of roaming marauders seeking to leave their mark on the galactic stage. In an apparent bid to recall the old legends of pre-shutdown pirate might, some captured Albatross builders have resurfaced as massive pirate scavenger-carriers, heavily modified but clearly recognizable, serving as flagships for the most successful pirate warlords. Dubbed the Galleon, these ad-hoc warships are a rare sight despite the proliferation of the Pact- a testament to the difficulty of procuring such a vessel given the unruly nature of pirate warbands and the significantly limited resources available to the pirates. \n\nWith its primary purpose being to visually demonstrate the power of their warlord-captains, the Galleon eschews defensive measures, with only modest shielding for its class and no point defense emplacements. In exchange, the ship boasts one of the heaviest armaments of any Commonwealth vessel: a formidable battery of 12 large turrets, often fitted with an eclectic loadout of whatever was on hand at the time, supported by abundant internal hangar space and numerous small ship landing pads. Beyond it's own capabilities, a Galleon is also inevitably accompanied by a full warband of pirates- motley swarms containing any number of attending vessels of all sizes. The arrival of a Galleon-led Warlord fleet presents a grave threat to any civilian or military asset in the system, and those few examples that are successfully wrested away from pirate control are jealously guarded trophies. </t>
	  <t id="801">Another revived design borne of the increasing cooperation within the Scale Plate Pact, the Blastclaw bomber is a remarkably capable ship and is a common sight in among larger pirate flotillas, both escorting larger vessels and operating as an independent strike wing. \n\nThough rather slow, the ship is well-shielded and features a heavily reinforced hull. However, the true strength of the bomber lies in the Incendiary Bomb Mortar mounted under the cockpit, capable of rapidly blasting away exposed surface elements and weakening shielded hulls. Even a single Blastclaw poses a deadly threat to poorly defended freighters, while a sufficient number of them can even challenge and disarm a destroyer, leaving it disabled and vulnerable to boarding actions undertaken by larger ships.</t>	
	  <t id="802">One of the larger threats in regular use by the Scale Plate Pact, the Brigantine is a heavily armed capital ship that can pose a significant threat even to military forces. Found almost anywhere that Scale Plate pirates operate and fulfilling any role demanded of it from solo raider to warband leader, the ship's pervasive presence in pirate fleets is owed primarily to its relative ease of acquisition. As many observers have concluded from it's appearance, the Brigantine is cobbled together by pirate shipwrights using the hull sections of Teladi auxiliary ships and carriers- scavenged from battlefield wrecks, decommissioned hulks and even the occasional captured prize. As with the Galleon, rumors abound of the Scale Plate Pact employing less overt means of acquiring these hulls through independent purchasers or unscrupulous Teladi officials, though the Teladi Company vehemently denies the rumors as slander and the Pact remains characteristically cagey with its secrets. \n\nIn the battlespace, the Brigantine employs a typically mismatched grab bag of weaponry and shielding, with the pirates making up what they lack in sophistication or planning with enthusiasm and sheer volume of fire. A handful of docking pads and launch tubes- remnants of the original ships that make up the hull- allows the Brigantine to deploy and support a small wing of fighters or drones to bolster its already-formidable firepower, while cavernous cargo capacity alleviates any need to be picky with plundered loot. Even the sheer imposing size of the vessel offers another weapon in the form of a menacing intimidation factor against civilian freighters. However, the design has numerous flaws as well- the nature of the Brigantine's construction leaves it with a weak hull structure for a ship of its size, a problem made worse by the relatively limited shielding and subpar speed. The substantial armament is also widely distributed across the hull, leaving few blind spots but in turn greatly degrading the ship's ability to concentrate fire.</t>
	  <t id="803">CARRACK DESCR</t>
	  <t id="804">Another of the Scale Plate Pact's homegrown designs, the Marauder corvette was first created in an act of desperation by a mechanically inclined Pact captain whose Minotaur Raider had been crippled in a raid gone awry. Though he managed to limp back to a hidden freeport, survival was only the first of his problems. Financially destitute, with a shattered ship and a crew on the verge of desertion, the captain - one Iljorgawas Minanoros Ioannis XII - noticed that although the central section of his Minotaur was little more than twisted scrap, the critical forward control and the aft machinery sections were still mostly intact. Struck by a flash of inspiration, he managed to cajole a little more faith from his crew and spent the next several days cutting out the damaged central section of his ship and reconnecting the two remaining portions. A few modifications later, he and his crew once again headed out in what would become the template design for the Marauder. \n\nAs the smallest medium-class ship currently found in the Gate Network, the Marauder specializes in attacking smaller foes while running from larger ones with its good agility and comparatively high speed. A varied collection of armaments - a pair of M-class fixed mounts, a single M-class turret, and four S-class fixed mounts thrown in for good measure - gives the ship good striking power against small transporters or enemy fighters, while the surprisingly capacious cargo storage for its size allows SCA freebooters to haul home their spoils. In exchange, the poor shielding, somewhat questionable hull strength, and anemic armament for its weight class leaves the ship with unfavorable odds when facing other corvettes or even a particularly ornery heavy fighter pilot. Nonetheless, its low operating costs and cheap construction price(often made cheaper through the use of written-off Minotaurs, like the original) ensure its place as a mainstay among the Scale Plate Pact pirates.</t>
	  <t id="805">Designed to support a large crew for extended raids, the interior is a cramped and barely livable mess, with hastily retrofitted bunks and repurposed cargo holds serving as crew quarters. Like most Raider-class ships, it is poorly maintained, often battle-scarred, and held together by desperation and necessity. With a reputation of a deathtrap, the Osprey Raider is a ship that only the most daring - or reckless - pirates would dare call home.\n\nTo compensate for its added weight, two additional engines have been haphazardly grafted onto the hull, giving the Osprey Raider a surprising turn of speed, unsurprisingly - at the cost of reliability. The original landing pad has been completely stripped out, replaced with an oversized torpedo storage bay and launch tubes, allowing it to unleash devastating barrages far beyond what a typical corvette could manage.</t>
	  <t id="806">Fitted with multiple turrets, the Vulture Raider boasts significantly improved defensive firepower compared to its civilian counterpart. However, like most Raider-class vessels, it is a patchwork of modifications, often poorly maintained and riddled with jury-rigged systems. Its cramped and barely livable interior reflects its purpose - mixing relatively high cargo space with extreme defensive capabilities while minimizing anything unrelated to profit or survival.\n\nA far cry from even the poorly-kept Vulture freighters of legitimate merchants, the Vulture Raider is typically riddled with external damage, missing panels, and exposed wiring. Its extremely low resale value makes it a ship that few would willingly purchase - except for those desperate or reckless enough to take advantage of its firepower and hauling capacity, regardless of the risks.</t>
	  <!--iSHIELDS-->
	  <t id="900">IG XL - Galleon Internal Generator</t>
	  <t id="901">IG S - Blastclaw Internal Generator</t>	
	  <t id="902">IG L - Brigantine Internal Generator</t>
	  <t id="903">IG L - Carrack Internal Generator</t>
	  <t id="904">IG M - Marauder Internal Generator</t>
	</page>
  </add>
  <replace sel="/language/page[@id='20221']/t[@id='3061']/text()[1]">Cruiser</replace>
  <replace sel="/language/page[@id='20221']/t[@id='3062']/text()[1]">Heavier than a Destroyer, ships of this class are far better better against capital ships and stations but are extremely vulnerable to smaller ships.</replace>   
</diff>  