<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<content id="ws_2653753970" name="Mining, Gas Collector and Raw Scrap Converter Stations" description="This mod adds mining stations for ore, silicon, ice and nividium, collector stations for methane, helium and hydrogen as well as converter stations for raw scrap.&#13;&#10;Energy cells are needed to mine the minerals, gases and raw scrap, with one energy cell producing one mineral, gas or scrap.&#13;&#10;To meet the high demand for energy cells, two modules for energy cell production are also offered.&#13;&#10;&#13;&#10;The AI does not build these stations. &#13;&#10;They are available as blueprints from the factions and can be built anywhere like normal stations / station modules. Therefore, they do not need resource deposits, asteroid fields, gas clouds or similar. &#13;&#10;&#13;&#10;==================================================&#13;&#10;&#13;&#10;This mod needs only the Cradle of Humanity DlC.&#13;&#10;Those who do not own this DlCs should use the &quot;vanilla&quot; Version: [url=https://steamcommunity.com/sharedfiles/filedetails/?id=2671893439]Mineral Mining and Gas Collector Stations (no DlCs)[/url]&#13;&#10;&#13;&#10;The mod supports the other DlCs. I set an optional dependency. So it is possible to buy the blueprints at the split and avarice factions and from the boron.&#13;&#10;If you do not own the other DlCs, you will get errors in your debug log, if you have activated it. But there should be no problems while gaming.&#13;&#10;&#13;&#10;Optionally the SirNukes Mod Support API Mod is required, more details below at &quot;Research and Cheat Options&quot;:&#13;&#10;[url]https://steamcommunity.com/workshop/filedetails/?id=2042901274[/url]&#13;&#10;&#13;&#10;==================================================&#13;&#10;&#13;&#10;Those who use the [b]Star Wars Interworlds[/b] mod, v0.70 and higher, please use following version instead:&#13;&#10;https://steamcommunity.com/sharedfiles/filedetails/?id=3429328469&#13;&#10;&#13;&#10;Note: This is still a beta version. So far everything should work, but unfortunately I didn't have enough time to test everything in every situation. &#13;&#10;&#13;&#10;==================================================&#13;&#10;&#13;&#10;[b]Mining Stations[/b]&#13;&#10;&#13;&#10;There are large mining stations, which use a minimalised model of the headquarters with three different asteroids. They can be bought as blueprints from all races.&#13;&#10;Currently the production cycle is 12 minutes, with up to 120k nividium, 600k ice and 2 mio ore or silicon produced per hour.&#13;&#10;In addition, small mining stations are offered by the community of planets and by the Terrans. These stations are cheaper, require a fortieth of the energy for production, but also produce only a fortieth: 3k nividium, 15k ice and 50k ore or silicon per hour&#13;&#10;&#13;&#10;[b]Gas Collector Stations[/b]&#13;&#10;&#13;&#10;The Gas Collector Stations are available in normal and small versions from the Terrans and from the other races.&#13;&#10;They produce up to 125k helium, 200k methane and 75k hydrogen per hour, the small stations also a tenth each.&#13;&#10;&#13;&#10;[b]Raw Scrap Converter Stations[/b].&#13;&#10;&#13;&#10;These stations exploit old shipwrecks and convert the raw scrap into general purpose scrap. They produce up to 22500 scrap per hour. They are also available from almost all races.&#13;&#10;&#13;&#10;[b]Energy Cell Productions[/b]&#13;&#10;&#13;&#10;Similar to the mining stations, the output of these stations has also increased with update 1.7. The large station produces 6 million energy cells per hour, the small one 600k.&#13;&#10;&#13;&#10;==================================================&#13;&#10;&#13;&#10;[b]Research and Cheat Options[/b]&#13;&#10;&#13;&#10;Since update 1.7, it is possible not only to buy station blueprints, but also to research them. This works just like the rest of the game's research. A lot of resources and a little bit of time are needed.&#13;&#10;By default, the research of blueprints of the player race are available. So that the research menu does not overflow. This can be changed via the mod options in the extension options. This requires the SirNukes mod support API mod:&#13;&#10;[url]https://steamcommunity.com/workshop/filedetails/?id=2042901274[/url]&#13;&#10;&#13;&#10;Also, there is now the option to get station blueprints for free via the same menu.&#13;&#10;&#13;&#10;Feedback on the update is always welcome.&#13;&#10;&#13;&#10;==================================================&#13;&#10;&#13;&#10;You think the building times are to long? Use the following mod additionally to reduce them to 60 seconds. Just download it and unzip it into the &quot;extensions&quot; folder.&#13;&#10;Download: [url]https://www.dropbox.com/s/ronk0j2nxom8eqw/mining_station_60s.zip?dl=0[/url]&#13;&#10;&#13;&#10;If you want to add changes to the mod in general, you should use the following Dropbox download, because all data is already unpacked here and a possible mod update won't break your changes.&#13;&#10;&#13;&#10;Download: [url]https://www.dropbox.com/s/tsj2p54lrmdvp8j/mining_station.zip?dl=0[/url]&#13;&#10;&#13;&#10;How and where to make changes for other production rates or the influence of the labour force are described in the readme and in the wares.xml.&#13;&#10;&#13;&#10;[b]Special thank to[/b]&#13;&#10;&#13;&#10;- iforgotmysocks, Egosoft-forum and Nexusmods: Update and notification routine. Thank you for letting me crip and adapt your code!&#13;&#10;- kuertee, Egosoft-forum and Nexusmods: Options for mods within the game (extension options). Same reason. Thank you very much!&#13;&#10;- aladinaleks, Steam: Russian translation and general support&#13;&#10;- cyno op, Steam: Chinese translation" author="sprIder" version="174" date="2024-05-11" save="0" lastupdate="1715454266">
  <text language="7" name="Mining, Gas Collector and Raw Scrap Converter Stations" description="Станции для добычи минералов с астероидов, сбора газов и переработки обломков из окружающего космоса. Для работы станций необходимы батарейки." author="sprIder"></text>
  <text language="33" name="Mining, Gas Collector and Raw Scrap Converter Stations" description="Stations that exploit the universe using energy cells to produce minerals, gas and scrap." author="sprIder"></text>
  <text language="34" name="Mining, Gas Collector and Raw Scrap Converter Stations" description="Stations that exploit the universe using energy cells to produce minerals, gas and scrap." author="sprIder"></text>
  <text language="39" name="Mining, Gas Collector and Raw Scrap Converter Stations" description="Stations that exploit the universe using energy cells to produce minerals, gas and scrap." author="sprIder"></text>
  <text language="44" name="Mining, Gas Collector and Raw Scrap Converter Stations" description="Stations that exploit the universe using energy cells to produce minerals, gas and scrap." author="sprIder"></text>
  <text language="49" name="Bergbau-, Gas Sammel- und Rohschrott Konverterstationen" description="Stationen, die mit Hilfe von Energiezellen das Universum ausbeuten und so Mineralien, Gas und Schrott gewinnen." author="sprIder"></text>
  <text language="55" name="Mining, Gas Collector and Raw Scrap Converter Stations" description="Stations that exploit the universe using energy cells to produce minerals, gas and scrap." author="sprIder"></text>
  <text language="81" name="Mining, Gas Collector and Raw Scrap Converter Stations" description="Stations that exploit the universe using energy cells to produce minerals, gas and scrap." author="sprIder"></text>
  <text language="82" name="Mining, Gas Collector and Raw Scrap Converter Stations" description="Stations that exploit the universe using energy cells to produce minerals, gas and scrap." author="sprIder"></text>
  <text language="86" name="Mining, Gas Collector and Raw Scrap Converter Stations" description="Stations that exploit the universe using energy cells to produce minerals, gas and scrap。" author="sprIder"></text>
  <text language="88" name="Mining, Gas Collector and Raw Scrap Converter Stations" description="Stations that exploit the universe using energy cells to produce minerals, gas and scrap。" author="sprIder"></text>
  <dependency name="Cradle of Humanity" id="ego_dlc_terran" optional="false"></dependency>
  <dependency name="Split Vendetta" id="ego_dlc_split" optional="true"></dependency>
  <dependency name="Tides of Avarice" id="ego_dlc_pirate" optional="true"></dependency>
  <dependency name="Kingdom End" id="ego_dlc_boron" optional="true"></dependency>
  <dependency name="SirNukes Mod Support APIs" id="ws_2042901274" optional="true"></dependency>
</content>
