<?xml version="1.1" encoding="utf-8"?>
<content id="ws_3529947103" name="Rackham class missile corvette" description="[h1] Rackham class missile corvette [/h1]&#13;&#10;&#13;&#10;After the Vigor Syndicate designed the Jager their engineers continued to revise and Experiment on the Baldur class hull, While the Jager was great for defending the Syndicate's most important assets and large vessels, it lacked the capabilities to be used in any meaningful offensive capacity, or even for its pirate raids into foreign space.&#13;&#10;&#13;&#10;The syndicate wanted a corvette that truly embodied the syndicate's style of combat, maneuverable, fast, light, and armed to the teeth, and as such, the Rackham was born.&#13;&#10;&#13;&#10;This vessel was an almost complete rebuild of the Baldur and Jager hulls, expanding the size of its central section, adding two VTOL engine pods to the outer ends of the ship's hull, and removing much of the turret hardpoints that were added before. Instead, a new, domestically designed missile launcher was mounted underneath the the hull, and advanced targeting sensors were integrated into the ship, along with an additional shield generator.&#13;&#10;&#13;&#10;The armament of the Rackham consists out of two defensive turrets, mounted on the top of the ship, and the advanced &quot;Boucan&quot; missile launcher, a rapid fire, VLS missile system capable of firing at targets within a large forward facing arc.&#13;&#10;&#13;&#10;These upgrades made the Rackham significantly more expensive than planned, but it also made it one of the strongest corvettes in the known galaxy, with significantly increased speed, excellent maneuverability, and powerful armament, a real force to be reckoned with, especially by larger destroyers and capital ships.&#13;&#10;  &#13;&#10;The Rackham quickly gained the attention from other pirates and outlaws, with the Scaleplate Pact especially eager to get their hands on a number of these corvettes for their own nefarious purposes.&#13;&#10;&#13;&#10;[h1] what does this mod change [/h1]&#13;&#10;&#13;&#10;it adds an all new M class ship to the VIG syndicate wharf, as well as in some sector patrols and VIG pirate fleets, its also included into the SCA pirate fleets.  &#13;&#10;﻿&#13;&#10;Its equipped with 2 M turret slots, and a single, rapid fire VLS missile launcher main weapon that works similar to that of the Sapporo, its capable of attaining a decent top speed and is maneuverable, and its increased shield strength helps it survive its initial encounter with the enemy. Its balanced by a limited munition storage, its relatively mediocre defensive armament, and lack of any forward facing main guns.  &#13;&#10;&#13;&#10;Supports custom paint jobs, and there's an optional VRO patch." author="eva" version="100" date="2025-07-27" save="0" lastupdate="1753583033">
  <text language="7" name="Rackham" description="Adds the Rackham to the Argon wharf" author="eva"/>
  <text language="33" name="Rackham" description="Adds the Rackham to the Argon wharf" author="eva"/>
  <text language="34" name="Rackham" description="Adds the Rackham to the Argon wharf" author="eva"/>
  <text language="39" name="Rackham" description="Adds the Rackham to the Argon wharf" author="eva"/>
  <text language="44" name="Rackham" description="Adds the Rackham to the Argon wharf" author="eva"/>
  <text language="45" name="Rackham" description="Adds the Rackham to the Argon wharf" author="eva"/>
  <text language="49" name="Rackham" description="Adds the Rackham to the Argon wharf" author="eva"/>
  <text language="81" name="Rackham" description="Adds the Rackham to the Argon wharf" author="eva"/>
  <text language="82" name="Rackham" description="Adds the Rackham to the Argon wharf" author="eva"/>
  <text language="86" name="Rackham" description="Adds the Rackham to the Argon wharf" author="eva"/>
  <text language="88" name="Rackham" description="Adds the Rackham to the Argon wharf" author="eva"/>
</content>
