<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<content name="Mobile Repair Service" id="ws_1683361083" author="Assailer" version="137" date="2022-06-15" save="0" description="Using this mod allows you to assign ships for repair duty. &#13;&#10;&#13;&#10;Hail the selected player owned ship (preferably a fast ship!) and tell the pilot to 'Start Repair Service' (find it under 'more' submenu), or using the detailed map information menus manually select default order and the sector to operate in. Once the script is running, you will also be able to change the home sector here.&#13;&#10;&#13;&#10;The pilot will look for the closest damaged player ship in the sector, or it will look for friendly ships in repair need.&#13;&#10;&#13;&#10;It's important to mention it will only repair ships with at least 20% charged shield.&#13;&#10;Having shields up a little usually means that ship has been out of combat for some time (successfully fled from battle), so it's safe to approach.&#13;&#10;&#13;&#10;The visited ship will get their engine/weapon/shield modules inspected after main hull was repaired. Those repairs will be listed under the 'List of repairs' section. Module repairs are trickier and they will cost 3x the usual hull repairs.&#13;&#10;&#13;&#10;The repair cost is based on management and engineering skills. When both skills are at minimal levels repairs will cost 6 credit/hull on both your and other faction's ships. When skills are at max (5 stars both) this will drop repair cost to 1 credit/hull for you, while it earns 21 credits/hull on repairs done on other faction's ships.&#13;&#10;&#13;&#10;Repair is done immediately on arrival to damaged ship to avoid endless chasing around. Delay after repairs however is based on engineering skill. 5 to 35 seconds. High engineering skill mean less waiting around.&#13;&#10;&#13;&#10;There is a delay between visiting ships and it is controlled by the piloting skills. 1 to 16 seconds.&#13;&#10;&#13;&#10;Pilots will earn experience on successful repairs, major xp for piloting and engineering, while minor xp on management and morale.&#13;&#10;&#13;&#10;To stop the repair mode, hail the pilot again and select 'Stop Repair Service', or using map change the default order to something else. Giving FlyTo commands will pause this script, so make sure no leftover 'waiting' is pending on temporary order list.&#13;&#10;&#13;&#10;It is now possible to select another ship to follow (like fleet support). This ship must be M/L/XL size class.&#13;&#10;&#13;&#10;Version 7.x compatible.&#13;&#10;&#13;&#10;Changes:&#13;&#10;1.01 - moved command texts to T files to support other languages.&#13;&#10;1.02 - removed unused highway parameter from move_to command. added boost option the same time.&#13;&#10;1.03 - in case target moves away, the repair ship will try to chase it for some time before marking it 'unreachable'&#13;&#10;1.04 - added interrupt handlers&#13;&#10;1.05 - repair service will take orders from friendly NPC and charge them double cost. Repair cost can be edited in mobilerepairservice.xml file line 14: $credit_per_hull. Thanks TheEarl for the NPC idea!&#13;&#10;1.06 - added Russian translations. Thanks Alexalsp!&#13;&#10;1.07 - fixed on START the pilot will set new home sector. Thanks RudolphleBreton for reporting!&#13;&#10;1.08 - added German translations. Thanks X2return! Changed the way credits are calculated.&#13;&#10;1.09 - added proper default ship order. Removed name tagging. For existing users, you will need to revisit your repairers and hail them to start repair mode again.&#13;&#10;1.11 - added submodule repair checks after main hull is fixed.&#13;&#10;1.12 - added skill based repair actions&#13;&#10;1.13 - engineer pilots will earn experience (minor management, normal engineering and piloting skills)&#13;&#10;1.14/15 - translations, text coloring. Thanks Alexalsp!&#13;&#10;1.18 - version 3.0 compatibility changes and fixed home sector tracking.&#13;&#10;1.20 - added sector selector to ship order menu.&#13;&#10;1.23 - added self repair. suggested by @wanderer from EGO forums.&#13;&#10;1.24 - added missing icon. no more question marks!&#13;&#10;1.25 - moved chat option behind submenu 'more'&#13;&#10;1.26 - added option to set work area by following another ship. Thanks Delliahwild!&#13;&#10;1.27 - removed check to require a pilot on the followed ship. Thanks Delilahwild for reporting!&#13;&#10;1.28 - added possibility to ignore specific factions. Thanks Truthowl and Holyvision for the idea!&#13;&#10;1.30 - after all repairs are done the nearest friendly station is visited for safety. Thanks Jgz for the idea!&#13;&#10;1.31 - added checks for turret repairs as well. Thanks JMRCaesar for reporting this bug!&#13;&#10;1.34 - added options to ignore target's shield levels (in case you want to risk your mechanic might get into battle), and option to ONLY repair player ships (this gives priority in a war zone).&#13;&#10;1.35 - compatibility fix for 4.10. Thanks Snork for the warning!&#13;&#10;1.36 - compatibility fix for 5.0&#13;&#10;&#13;&#10;&#13;&#10;[h1]Assailer's X4 mods:[/h1]&#13;&#10;[url=https://steamcommunity.com/sharedfiles/filedetails/?id=1683359513]Secret Stash[/url]&#13;&#10;[url=https://steamcommunity.com/sharedfiles/filedetails/?id=1683356126]Fly-by Lockbox[/url]&#13;&#10;[url=https://steamcommunity.com/sharedfiles/filedetails/?id=1683358279]Fly-by Looting[/url]&#13;&#10;[url=https://steamcommunity.com/sharedfiles/filedetails/?id=1683361083]Mobile Repair Service[/url]&#13;&#10;[url=https://steamcommunity.com/sharedfiles/filedetails/?id=1768106576]Capital Ship Loot Magnet[/url]&#13;&#10;[url=https://steamcommunity.com/sharedfiles/filedetails/?id=2063916598]Inventory Collector[/url]&#13;&#10;[url=https://steamcommunity.com/sharedfiles/filedetails/?id=2074838459]Sector Explorer[/url]&#13;&#10;&#13;&#10;" lastupdate="1655313191">
  <text language="7" name="Mobile Repair Service" description="Мобильная Служба Ремонта"></text>
  <text language="33" name="Mobile Repair Service" description="Mobile Repair Service"></text>
  <text language="34" name="Mobile Repair Service" description="Mobile Repair Service"></text>
  <text language="39" name="Mobile Repair Service" description="Mobile Repair Service"></text>
  <text language="44" name="Mobile Repair Service" description="Mobile Repair Service"></text>
  <text language="49" name="Mobiler Reparatur Service" description="Ein Spieler-kontrolliertes Schiff kann mit Reparaturen beauftragt werden.\n Schnelle Schiffe sind vorteilhaft."></text>
  <text language="86" name="Mobile Repair Service" description="Mobile Repair Service"></text>
  <text language="88" name="Mobile Repair Service" description="Mobile Repair Service"></text>
</content>
