<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<content name="Sector Explorer" id="ws_2074838459" author="Assailer" version="148" date="2025-04-08" save="0" description="Sector Explorer&#13;&#10;&#13;&#10;This mod adds a new default job option for your pilots. Use a fast ship for this job.&#13;&#10;&#13;&#10;Pilots assigned to sector explorer duty will travel around the sector to visit unknown stations, gates, highways, then when all are discovered, they will fly an accurate 300-900km radius hexagon shape.&#13;&#10;&#13;&#10;Under 'Individual Instructions' tab adjust 'Sector Travel/Sector Activities' as necessary. For example:&#13;&#10;- create activities blacklist where you select 'Sectors owned by enemies' and/or,&#13;&#10;- create travel blacklist where you select both 'Sectors owned by enemies' and 'Sectors containing dangerous regions'.&#13;&#10;Make sure you tick off the 'default' and point to your newly created blacklists under individual instructions tab.&#13;&#10;&#13;&#10;To start the mod, open ship information behavior panel and select 'Sector Explorer' from navigation jobs.&#13;&#10;&#13;&#10;Captains earn piloting experience after completing each hexagon round cycle that are further than 150km from center.&#13;&#10;&#13;&#10;Sector Core is set by the developers individual to each sector and is almost never at [0,0,0], but there is checkbox option to force using [0,0,0] in case you wish to. Default is to use Core parameter.&#13;&#10;&#13;&#10;The Log is updated on start/stop events, and there will also be a popup message for stop events if the 'Notifications' option is set.&#13;&#10;&#13;&#10;Enjoy.&#13;&#10;&#13;&#10;Version 7.x compatible.&#13;&#10;&#13;&#10;*** Once the mod is considered 'feature ready' it will be also copied to nexusmods ***&#13;&#10;&#13;&#10;Changes:&#13;&#10;1.00 - initial public release&#13;&#10;1.01 - fixed notification text popup to print ship + sector names.&#13;&#10;1.02 - added Russian translation. Thanks aladinaleks!&#13;&#10;1.03 - using 'coresize' sector specific parameter instead a fixed 450km range. added piloting xp.&#13;&#10;1.04 - Decreased exploration height and increased little bit the exploration radius.&#13;&#10;1.05 - added parameter which allows choosing exploration center position. by default it will be the sectorcore, but can be [0,0,0] in case you like it better that way.&#13;&#10;1.06 - added code to visit unknown stations after exploration cycle to make sure everything gets discovered.&#13;&#10;1.08 - script will remember exploration progress and tries to resume after temp order was completed. leaving sector will reset progress.&#13;&#10;1.09 - the station exploration stage will skip visiting enemy stations.&#13;&#10;1.10 - added option to disable hexagon pattern search. also option to enable scanning for lockboxes.&#13;&#10;1.11 - added 'continue to next sector' parameter. &#13;&#10;1.12 - changed execution order to visit unknown stations before pattern flight. Thanks Arthur for suggesting this!&#13;&#10;1.13 - added randomization when pilot selects a next sector&#13;&#10;1.14 - fixed syntax error - Thanks tizuby for reporting this!&#13;&#10;1.15 - added blacklist to avoid exploring specific sectors.&#13;&#10;1.17 - added global blacklist support (civilian - sector activity) - Thanks Mysterius for the idea!&#13;&#10;1.18 - added maximum exploration range slider. - Thanks Alewx for the idea!&#13;&#10;1.19 - moved parameter texts to separate text definition file to be possible to localize them.&#13;&#10;1.20 - added Chinese translation - Thanks Cyno Up!&#13;&#10;1.21 - changed the way the sector is revealed. Instead flying around, the explorer sends out advanced satellites for a few seconds to get much nicer results. If there is 'dislike' from players, i will revert to old flying method, or add it back as alternative.&#13;&#10;1.22 - added option to re-enable the original flying method to deal with fog of war (Satellite probes will use new method). You may need to toggle this switch on/off, so the script will recognize its current state. &#13;&#10;1.23 - changed default exploration method back to flying. &#13;&#10;1.24 - fixed satellite explorer method.&#13;&#10;1.25 - updated Russian texts. Thanks Aladinaleks!&#13;&#10;1.26 - added parameter to adjust exploration ring distances in 40km-100km range. Thanks Terran for the idea!&#13;&#10;1.27 - added German translation. Thanks 'FAIL! Chapi'!&#13;&#10;1.28 - added option to scan for abandoned ships&#13;&#10;1.30 - added option to disable station visits. Thanks Lobo for the idea!&#13;&#10;1.31 - updated Rus texts thanks Aladinaleks!&#13;&#10;1.32 - added option to visit data vaults (Thanks Aladinaleks for the idea and sample code!)&#13;&#10;1.34 - added travel blacklist check&#13;&#10;1.36 - added Italian translation (Thanks setebro93!)&#13;&#10;1.37 - simplified blacklists, read description for details&#13;&#10;1.38 - refactored the entire mod. Explorer ships will sync their travel plans between each other and the galaxy wide tracking system will also remember the fog of war progress. You may need to cancel and reassign default job to avoid erroneous behaviors. &#13;&#10;1.41 - fixed those reported issues, thanks Nermal! in addition, added a new option 'Reset progress' which when &quot;turned on -&gt; commit changes -&gt; turned off -&gt;commit changes&quot; should erase hexagon exploration progress for that specific sector the ship is located in (in case you want to re-trigger hexagon trip).&#13;&#10;1.42 - added option to allow turning off popup notifications (on by default after fresh assignments)&#13;&#10;1.43 - update Russian translation (Thanks Aladinaleks!)&#13;&#10;1.44 - should be fully 7.0 compatible, fixed a bug in sector change code when all gates are known. (Thanks AlwaysRLYAngry for reporting)&#13;&#10;1.45 - increased the wait time for hexagon corners, let's see if this helps with the fog removal.&#13;&#10;1.46 - disabled logfile spam for manual operation. (Thanks Szorrin for reporting)&#13;&#10;1.47 - added mimic support. Thanks DannCi for the pastebin solution!&#13;&#10;1.48 - disabled vault options until it gets fixed&#13;&#10;&#13;&#10;[h1]Assailer's X4 mods:[/h1]&#13;&#10;[url=https://steamcommunity.com/sharedfiles/filedetails/?id=1683359513]Secret Stash[/url]&#13;&#10;[url=https://steamcommunity.com/sharedfiles/filedetails/?id=1683356126]Fly-by Lockbox[/url]&#13;&#10;[url=https://steamcommunity.com/sharedfiles/filedetails/?id=1683358279]Fly-by Looting[/url]&#13;&#10;[url=https://steamcommunity.com/sharedfiles/filedetails/?id=1683361083]Mobile Repair Service[/url]&#13;&#10;[url=https://steamcommunity.com/sharedfiles/filedetails/?id=1768106576]Capital Ship Loot Magnet[/url]&#13;&#10;[url=https://steamcommunity.com/sharedfiles/filedetails/?id=2063916598]Inventory Collector[/url]&#13;&#10;" lastupdate="1744109887">
  <text language="7" name="Sector Explorer" description="Мод предназначен для исследования секторов."></text>
  <text language="86" name="Sector Explorer" description="星区探索"></text>
  <text language="33" name="Sector Explorer" description="Sector Explorer"></text>
  <text language="34" name="Sector Explorer" description="Sector Explorer"></text>
  <text language="39" name="Sector Explorer" description="Esplorazione del settore"></text>
  <text language="44" name="Sector Explorer" description="Sector Explorer"></text>
  <text language="49" name="Sector Explorer" description="Der Sektor Explorer erkundet automatisch den Sektor."></text>
  <text language="88" name="Sector Explorer" description="Sector Explorer"></text>
</content>
